Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
- Correspondence - subject files
  - Robbins, Jack Alan, 1967-1978; undated; 15 folders (Box 52)
  - Robbins, Jack Alan "Marxism and Literature in the 1930s" (Box 52)
  - Robbins, Jack Alan (Box 52)
    See also "The Past Recaptured" and "Ripples in the American Stream" in Arvin, Newton.
  - Roberts, Holland (Box 53)
  - Roberts, Lester (Box 53)
  - Robinson, Boardman (Box 53)
    See also Oversize material: Metropolitan selections.
  - Robinson, Bradley (Box 53)
  - Robinson, Earl (Box 53)
  - Robinson, Edwin Arlington (Box 53)
  - Robinson, Elmo A. (Box 53)
  - Rochester, Anna (Box 53)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1942-1969; undated; 2 folders (Box 53)
  - Rodehaver, Myles W. (Box 53)
  - Rodgers, Paul Cochrane (Box 53)
  - Rodman, Selden (Box 53)
  - Rofheart, Martha (Box 53)
  - Rohlfs, Anna Katharine (Green) (Box 53)
  - Rokotov, T., See International Literature.
  - Rollins, Alfred Brooks (Box 53)
  - Romaine, Paul (Box 53)
  - Ronald, James (Box 53)
  - Ronald Press Company (Box 53)
  - Roop, Wendell P. (Box 53)
  - Roper, Elmo (Box 53)
  - Rorem, Ned (Box 53)
  - Rorty, James (Box 53)
  - Rose, Alice (Box 53)
  - Rose, Thomas (Box 53)
  - Rose, William (Box 53)
  - Rosen, Aaron Tani (Box 53)
  - Rosenberg, Emily S. (Box 53)
  - Rosenberg, Marvin (Box 53)
  - Rosenfield, Leonora Cohen (Box 53)
  - Rosenhaupt, Hans (Box 53)
  - Rosenstone, Robert A. (Box 53)
  - Rosenthal, Raymond (Box 53)
  - Roskolenko, Harry (Box 53)
  - Ross, Edward Alsworth (Box 53)
  - Ross, Irwin (Box 53)
  - Rosset, Barney (Box 53)
  - Rossiter, Clinton Lawrence (Box 53)
  - Roth, Henry (Box 53)
  - Roth, Philip (Box 53)
  - Rothermel, Bertha M. (Box 53)
  - Rouillard, Henri (Box 53)
  - Rovere, Richard, 1936-1955; 1965; 3 folders (Box 53)
  - Rovere, Richard, undated; 6 folders (Box 54)
  - Rowlingson, Donald T. (Box 54)
  - Rubin, Jacob H. (Box 54)
  - Rueckert, William H. (Box 54)
  - Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 54)
  - Ruskin, John (Box 54)
  - Russak, Martin (Box 54)
  - Russell, Charles Edward (Box 54)
  - Russell, Diarmuid, See Volkening, Henry.
  - Russell and Russell, Inc. (Box 54)
  - Russell and Volkening, Inc., See Volkening, Henry.
  - SA - SH (Box 54)
  - SI - SZ (Box 54)
  - Saal, Rollene (Box 54)
  - Salinger, J.D., 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Saltus, Edgar (Box 54)
  - Salzman, Jack (Box 54)
  - Salzmann, Jerome (Box 54)
  - Sammons, Wheeler (Box 54)
  - Sanders, David Scott (Box 54)
  - Sangster, Ellen (Box 54)
  - Sapieha, Nicholas (Box 54)
  - Sargent, Porter (Box 54)
  - Sarlos, Robert Karoly (Box 54)
  - Sarton, May (Box 54)
  - Sartre, John Paul (Box 55)
  - Satterthwaite, Sheafe (Box 55)
  - Saturday Review
    - "Mail-Order Creativity", April 29, 1961; See "Mail-Order Creativity" response in Famous Writers School.
    - "The Right Word to Write", July 17, 1965 (Box 55)
    - "To Him Who Would a Writer Be", Jan. 1, 1966 (Box 55)
    - "The Wrong Word For It", May 7, 1966; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - "A Problem of Definition", Oct. 22, 1966 (Box 55)
    - "A Man of Many Words", Jan. 28, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "Each Generation Has Its Own Dream", Mar. 25, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "The Media Crisis in the Classroom", Apr. 15, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "Art Lost in Analysis", May 13, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "Dull For Bright Young Brains", July 8, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "Is English Getting Too Wordy", Oct. 28, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "More on Words", Dec. 23, 1967 (Box 55)
    - "Philology for Fun", Oct. 12, 1968; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Saturday Review (of Literature) (Box 55)
  - Saunders, Marion (Box 55)
  - Savage, George (Box 55)
  - Saveth, Edward Norman (Box 55)
  - Saxton, Mark (Box 55)
  - Sayre, Robert F. (Box 55)
  - Schachner, Eugene (Box 55)
  - Schacht, Marshall (Box 55)
  - Schapiro, Meyer (Box 55)
  - Schappes, Morris Urman (Box 55)
  - Schick, Frank Leopold (Box 55)
  - Schlatter, Richard Bulger (Box 55)
  - Schlauch, Margaret (Box 55)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Box 56)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur M. (Jr.) (Box 56)
  - Schlichtkrull, Thomas W. (Box 56)
  - Schmelzer, Richard W., 1959-1962; undated; 2 folders (Box 56)
  - Schmidt, James Norman (Box 56)
  - Schmitt, Gladys (Box 56)
  - Schneider, Harold W. (Box 56)
  - Schneider, Isidor (Box 56)
  - Schneider, Robert W. (Box 56)
  - Schneiderman, Rose (Box 56)
  - Schorer, Mark (Box 56)
  - Schroeter, James (Box 56)
  - Schulte, Rainer (Box 56)
  - Schuman, Frederick Lewis (Box 56)
  - Schwab, Arnold T. (Box 56)
  - Schwartz, Daniel Herbert (Box 56)
  - Schwartz, Delmore (Box 56)
  - Schwartzman, Ephraim (Box 56)
  - Science and Society, 1936-1939; undated (Box 56)
  - Scott, Arthur Lincoln (Box 56)
  - Scott, Evelyn (Box 56)
  - Scott, James (Box 56)
  - Scott, Leroy (Box 56)
  - Scott, Foresman and Co. (Box 56)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 56)
  - Seattle Repertory Playhouse (Box 56)
  - Seaver, Edwin (Box 56)
  - Seid, Ruth (Box 56)
  - Seidlin, Oskar (Box 56)
  - Seitz, Don Carlos (Box 56)
  - Serebnick, Judith (Box 56)
  - Sessions, Jack A. (Box 56)
  - Setian, Ralph (Box 56)
  - Settle, Mary Lee (Box 56)
  - Sewanee Review (Box 56)
  - Seward, William Ward (Box 56)
  - Shafer, Margaret (Box 56)
  - Shaffer, Thomas L. (Box 56)
  - Shannon, David A. (Box 56)
  - Shapiro, Charles (Box 56)
  - Shapiro, Herbert (Box 56)
  - Shapiro, Lionel S.B. (Box 56)
  - Shapley, Rufus Edmonds Solid For Mulhooly (Box 56)
  - Shaw, George Bernard (Box 56)
  - Shaw, Irwin (Box 56)
  - Shay, Frank (Box 56)
  - Sheaffer, Louis (Box 56)
  - Sheffeld, Marion (Box 57)
  - Shelley, Percy Bysshe (Box 57)
  - Shenandoah (Box 57)
  - Shepard, Odell (Box 57)
  - Sherman, Stuart (Box 57)
  - Shover, Michele (Box 57)
  - Shute, Nevil (Box 57)
  - Sichel, Pierre (Box 57)
  - Sickels, Dorothy Judd (Box 57)
  - Siena College (Box 57)
  - Silberstein, Joan, See Arnold, Joan.
  - Siler, Ruth, See Kaswan, Ruth Siler.
  - Sillars, Robertson (Box 57)
  - Sillen, Samuel (Box 57)
  - Simmons, Charles (Box 57)
  - Simmons, Ernest Joseph (Box 57)
  - Simon, Rita James (Box 57)
  - Simon and Schuster, Inc. (Box 57)
  - Simonson, Harold Peter (Box 57)
  - Simonson, Lee (Box 57)
  - Simpson, Claude Mitchell (Box 57)
  - Simpson, Herman (Box 57)
  - Sinclair, Jo, See Seid, Ruth.
  - Sinclair, Upton (Box 57)
  - Sipprell, Clara (Box 57)
  - Skidmore College (Box 57)
  - Sklar, Robert (Box 57)
  - Slade, Caroline (Beach) (Box 57)
  - Slade, John A. (Box 57)
  - Slatoff, Walter Jacob (and Jimmy) (Box 57)
  - Slawsky, Zaka (Box 57)
  - William Sloane Associates (Box 57)
  - Slochower, Harry (Box 57)
  - Small Town, 1946-1972; undated; 4 folders (Box 57)
  - Smedley, Agnes (Box 57)
  - Smith, Bernard (Box 57)
  - Smith, Bradford (Box 57)
  - Smith, Chard Powers (and Eunice), 1960-1981; undated; 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Smith, Datus Clifford, See Princeton University Press.
  - Smith, Francis Hopkinson (Box 58)
  - Smith, Glanville (Box 58)
  - Smith, Harrison (Box 58)
  - Smith, Henry Nash (Box 58)
  - Smith, Lillian (Box 58)
  - Smith, College (Box 58)
  - Snow, C.P. (Box 58)
  - Snow, Sinclair (Box 58)
  - Snow, Walter (Box 58)
  - Socialism bibliographies (Box 58)
  - Socialism - Book proposal and outline (Box 58)
  - Socialist Call (Box 58)
  - Society, Analysis of (Box 58)
  - Society of American Historians (Box 58)
  - Sosin, Gene (Box 58)
  - South Atlantic Quarterly (Box 58)
  - Southern Illinois University Press (Box 58)
  - Southern Review (Box 58)
  - Spadea Syndicate (Box 58)
  - Spaeth, Sigmund (Box 58)
  - Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc. (Box 58)
  - Spark, Muriel (Box 58)
  - Spark (Box 58)
  - "Speak for Yourself" (Box 58)
  - "Speaking of Books", 3 folders (Box 58)
  - Speight, Harold Edwin Balme (Box 58)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth (Box 58)
  - Spencer, Theodore (Box 58)
  - Spender, Stephen (Box 59)
  - Sperber, Manes (Box 59)
  - Spero, Sterling Denhard (Box 59)
  - Sperry, Willard Learoyd (Box 59)
  - Spinoza Institute of America (Box 59)
  - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts (Box 59)
  - Squires, James Duane (Box 59)
  - Stacton, David (Box 59)
  - Stafford, Jean (Box 59)
  - Stallings, Lawrence. Plumes (Box 59)
  - Standish, Robert (Box 59)
  - Starbuck, Kathryn H. (Box 59)
  - Starobin, Joseph Robert (Box 59)
  - Starr, Harris Elwood, See Dictionary of American Biography.
  - Startsev, Abel Isaakovich (Box 59)
  - State University College at Brockport (Box 59)
  - Stavis, Barrie (Box 59)
  - Stebel, S.L. (Box 59)
  - Steckmesser, Kent Ladd (Box 59)
  - Steel, Ronald (Box 59)
  - Steele, Mary Q. (Box 59)
  - Steep, Thomas (Box 59)
  - Steffens, Lincoln, 3 folders (Box 59)
  - Steffens, Lincoln. CBS Invitation to Learning, "Autobiography of Lincoln Steffens", Aug. 5, 1945 (Box 59)
  - Stegner, Wallace Earle (Box 59)
  - Stein, Sol (Box 59)
  - Stein and Day (publishers), See Stein, Sol.
  - Steinbeck, John (Box 59)
  - Steinberg, Julien (Box 59)
  - Steinman, (Miss), See Watkins, Shirley.
  - Stephen, Leslie (Box 59)
  - Stephenson, Howard (Box 59)
  - Stern, Bernhard Joseph (Box 59)
  - Stern, Madeleine Bettina (Box 59)
  - Stern, Richard G. (Box 59)
  - Stevens, A. Wilber (Box 59)
  - Stevens, Clarence Davis (Box 59)
  - Stevens, Doris (Box 59)
  - Stevens, James (Box 59)
  - Stevenson, Robert Louis (Box 59)
  - Steward, Donald Ogden (Box 59)
  - Stiver, Mary Weeden (Box 59)
  - Stone, Grace Zaring, See Vance, Ethel.
  - Stone, Robert (Box 59)
  - Stonequist, Everett vol. (Box 59)
  - Stonesifer, Richard James (Box 59)
  - Stott, William (Box 59)
  - Stowe, Harriet Beecher (Box 59)
  - Strachey, John (Box 59)
  - Strasburger, Victor C. (Box 60)
  - Strauss, Patricia (O'Flynn) (Box 60)
  - Stribling, Thomas Sigismund (Box 60)
  - Stromberg, Roland N. (Box 60)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Box 60)
  - Struther, Jan (Box 60)
  - Stuart, Jesse (Box 60)
  - Stuart, John, See Writings: Books: Stuart manuscript (Box 83)
  - Stubbs, Thomas (Box 60)
  - Stubing, Charles Harry (Box 60)
  - Student Federation of Religious Liberals, See Writings: Miscellany: Published: The Student Liberal.
  - Student Non-violent Coordinating Committee (Box 60)
  - Studies in Short Fiction (Box 60)
  - Styron, William (Box 60)
  - Suckow, Ruth (Box 60)
  - Sudermann, Hermann (Box 60)
  - Sulkin, Sidney (Box 60)
  - Sullivan, Frank (Box 60)
  - Summers, Hollis Spurgeon (Box 60)
  - Swados, Harvey (Box 60)
  - Swallow, Alan (Box 60)
  - Swanson, Walter (Box 60)
  - Sweeney, Frances (Box 60)
  - Sweezy, Paul Marlor (Box 60)
  - Swinburne, Algernon Charles (Box 60)
  - Switalski, John (Box 60)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard (Box 60)
  - Sykes, Gerald (Box 60)
  - Symes, Lillian (Box 60)
  - Syracuse 10 (Box 60)
  - Syracuse University (Box 60)
  - Syracuse University Library (Box 60)
  - Syracuse University Press (Box 60)
  - Szogyi, Alex (Box 60)
  - T (Box 60)
  - Taggard, Genevieve (Box 60)
  - Talmadge, Irving (Box 60)
  - Tamarack Review (Box 60)
  - Tamas, Istvan (Box 60)
  - Tarbell, Ida (Box 60)
  - Targ, William (Box 60)
  - Taylor, Frank (Box 60)
  - Taylor, Graham Romeyn (Box 61)
  - Taylor, Karl K. (Box 61)
  - Taylor, Sarah Wingate (Box 61)
  - Tax, E.H. (Box 61)
  - Tead, Ordway (Box 61)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 61)
  - Terzian, Lawrence (Box 61)
  - Thanet, Octave (Box 61)
  - There Was a Man in Our Town (Box 61)
  - Thibadeau, Arthur Thomas (Box 61)
  - Thirlwall, John Connop (Box 61)
  - Thomas, Margaret Loring (Box 61)
  - Thomas, Norman (Box 61)
  - Thompson, Dorothy (Box 61)
  - Thompson, Lawrence (Box 61)
  - Thoreau, Henry David (Box 61)
  - Thornton, M.B. (Box 61)
  - Thorp, Willard (Box 61)
  - Thurber, James (Box 61)
  - Thurman, Wallace (Box 61)
  - Tomorrow (magazine) (Box 61)
  - Tonks, Lewi (Box 61)
  - Tourgee, Albion W. (Box 61)
  - Toy, Eckard Vance (Box 61)
  - Toynbee, Arnold J., 2 folders (Box 61)
  - Toynbee, Arnold J. (Box 61)
    See also RPI Convocation, Church and Work Congress.
  - Tractenberg, Alexander, See International Publishers.
  - Trade unions (Box 61)
  - Tresca, Carlo (Box 61)
  - Trilling, Lionel (Box 61)
  - Trollope, Anthony (Box 61)
  - Trounstine, John J. (Box 61)
  - Troy, William (Box 61)
  - Troy Record (Box 61)
    See also Marvin, Dwight.
  - Trueblood, David Elton (Box 61)
  - Tsiang, H.T. (Box 61)
  - Tsugawa, Albert. The Idea of Criticism. (Box 61)
  - Turner, John Kenneth (Box 61)
  - Tuttleton, James W. (Box 61)
  - Twain, Mark, 2 folders (Box 61)
  - Twentieth Century Authors (Box 61)
  - Twersky, Jacob (Box 61)
  - U (Box 61)
  - Udmark, John Andersen (Box 61)
  - Ullman, Victor (Box 61)
  - Uman, Uta (Box 61)
  - Frederick Ungar Publishing Co. (Box 61)
  - Union College (Box 61)
  - Union for Democratic Action (Box 62)
  - United States. Department of Justice (Box 62)
  - United States. Treasury Department (Box 62)
  - United States - Economic conditions-19th century (Box 62)
  - United States - Economic conditions, 1918-1945; 4 folders (Box 62)
  - United States - History (Box 62)
  - United States - Intellectual life - Book proposals, 2 folders (Box 62)
  - United States Information Agency, 1950-1967; 2 folders (Box 62)
  - United States Steel Corporation. "Ten Years of Steel" (Box 62)
  - Unity (Box 62)
  - Universal Pictures Company, Inc. (Box 62)
  - University Microfilms (Box 62)
  - Unterecker, John Eugene (Box 62)
  - Updike, John (Box 63)
  - Utopias (Box 63)
  - V (Box 63)
  - Vagabond (Box 63)
  - Valles, Jules (Box 63)
  - Vance, Ethel (Box 63)
  - Vance, Louis Joseph (Box 63)
  - Vandenberg, T.F. (Box 63)
  - Van Doren, Mark (Box 63)
  - Van Dyke, Henry, b.1852 - d.1933 (Box 63)
  - Van Dyke, Henry (Box 63)
  - Vanguard Press, Inc. (Box 63)
  - Van Gundy, Justine (Box 63)
  - Van Neil, Eloise (Box 63)
  - Van Rensselaer, Philip (Box 63)
  - Van Schaick, John (Box 63)
  - Vaughan, Wayland Farries (Box 63)
  - Veblen, Thorstein (Box 63)
  - Vermilyea (Roy) case (Box 63)
  - Vickers, George Edward. The Fall of Bossism. (Box 63)
  - Vidal, Gore (Box 63)
  - Viereck, Peter Robert Edwin (Box 63)
  - Viking Press, Inc., 1933-1965; undated; 2 folders (Box 63)
  - Villa, Jose Garcia (Box 63)
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison (Box 63)
  - Vinal, Harold (Box 63)
  - Vinson, James (Box 63)
  - Vintage Books, Inc. (Box 63)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 63)
  - Vivante, Arturo (Box 63)
  - Vizetelly, Henry E. (Box 63)
  - Vogel, Joseph (Box 63)
  - Volkening, Henry, 1950-1963; 5 folders (Box 63)
  - Volkening, Henry, 1964-1975; 4 folders (Box 64)
  - Vonnegut, Kurt (Box 64)
  - Vorse, Mary Heaton (Box 64)
  - Vrettos, Theodore (Box 64)
  - W, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - WABY radio station, 2 folders (Box 64)
  - WAST (Channel 13) (Box 64)
  - WGY (radio station) (Box 64)
  - WNDC (radio station) Radio review for Behold Trouble (Box 64)
  - Wackerbarth, Doris H. (Box 64)
  - Wade, John Donald (Box 64)
  - Wager, Walter (Box 64)
  - Waggoner, Walter H. (Box 64)
  - Wagner, Geoffrey (Box 64)
  - Wait, Newman E. (Box 64)
  - "Wake Up, America!" Text of debate between Hicks and Ely Culbertson (Box 64)
  - Wald, Alan (Box 64)
  - Waldo, Octavia, See Locke, Octavia.
  - Walker, Dale (Box 64)
  - Walker, Ursula Genung, 1938-1946; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Walker, Ursula Genung, 1947-1969; 4 folders (Box 65)
  - Walker, Ursula Genung. "Structural Features of Negro English in Natchitoches Parish", thesis (Box 65)
  - Wall, Edward (and Geraldine) (Box 65)
  - Wallant, Edward Lewis (Box 65)
  - Wallis, Wilson Dallam (Box 65)
  - Walsh, Chad (Box 65)
  - Walsh, Richard John (Box 65)
  - Walter, Erich Albert (Box 65)
  - Walther, Margot (Box 65)
  - Walton, Eda Lou (Box 65)
  - Walton, Edith (Mrs. Lombard C. Jones), 1928-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 65)
  - Walton, Edith (Mrs. Lombard C. Jones) (Box 65)
    See also Jones, Lombard C..
  - Walts, Robert Warren (Box 65)
  - War books (Box 65)
  - War propaganda (Box 65)
  - Ward, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps). The Silent Partner (Box 65)
  - Ward, Lynd (Box 65)
  - Ward, Moira M. (Box 65)
  - Warfel, Harry Redcay (Box 65)
  - Warren, Austin (Box 65)
  - Warren, Robert Penn (Box 65)
  - Warshow, Robert Irving (Box 66)
  - Washburn, Owen R. (Box 66)
  - University of Washington Press (Box 66)
  - Wasser, Henry Hirsch (Box 66)
  - Wasserstrom, William (Box 66)
  - Watkins, Shirley (Box 66)
  - Watson, Goodwin Barbour (Box 66)
  - A.P. Watt & Son (Box 66)
  - Waugh, Evelyn (Box 66)
  - Wayne State University (Box 66)
  - Weaver, Gordon (Box 66)
  - Webb, Eleanor, 1937-1976; undated; 4 folders (Box 66)
  - Weber, Brom (Box 66)
  - Weber, Jean M. (Box 66)
  - Weber, Richard B. (Box 66)
  - Weber, Tom (Box 66)
  - Webster, Harvey Curtis, 1936-1963; 5 folders (Box 66)
  - Webster, Harvey Curtis, 1964-1974; undated; 6 folders (Box 67)
  - Webster, Sheridan (Box 67)
  - Wechsler, James Arthur (Box 67)
  - Weeks, Edward (Box 67)
  - Weiner, Albert B. (Box 67)
  - Weintraub, Stanley (Box 67)
  - Weisenburger, Walter B., Feb.17, 1942; Address (Box 67)
  - Weiss, Paul (Box 67)
  - Weller, Charles Frederick (Box 67)
  - Wells, Arvin R., See Ohio University.
  - Wells, Carlton Frank (Box 67)
  - Wells, H.G. (Box 67)
  - Wells College (Box 67)
  - Welty, Eudora (Box 67)
  - Wenning, Henry, 1964-1971; undated; 2 folders (Box 67)
  - Wescott, Glenway (Box 67)
  - Wesleyan University Press (Box 67)
  - West, Anthony (Box 67)
  - West, Elliot (Box 67)
  - West, Jessamyn (Box 67)
  - West, Nathanael (Box 67)
  - West Chester State College (Box 67)
  - Westbrook, Adele (Box 67)
  - Western American literature
    - Critique, vol. 2, no. 3, winter 1959 (Box 68)
    - Western American Literature, vol. 3, no. 3, fall 1968 (Box 68)
    - South Dakota Review, vol. 2, no. 1, autumn 1964 (Box 68)
  - Western Review (Box 68)
  - Western Writers of America (Box 68)
  - Westervelt, Virginia Veeder (Box 68)
  - Weston, Christine (Goutiere) (Box 68)
  - Wetzel, Donald (Box 68)
  - Wharton, Edith (Box 68)
  - Wheelock, Elizabeth (Box 68)
    See also Lancaster, Elizabeth G..
  - Wheelwright, John (Box 68)
  - Whelen, Christopher (Box 68)
  - Where We Came Out (Box 68)
  - Whipple, Charles L. (Box 68)
  - Whipple, Thomas King (Box 68)
  - Whisnant, Charleen (Box 68)
  - Whitbread, Thomas F. (Box 68)
  - Whitcomb, Robert (Box 68)
  - White, David Manning (Box 68)
  - White, Kenneth (Box 68)
  - White, Victor Francis (Box 68)
  - White, William (Box 68)
  - White, William Allen (Box 68)
  - Whiteing, Richard (Box 68)
  - Whitlock, Brand (Box 68)
  - Whitman, Walt (Box 68)
  - Wilcox, Ella Wheeler (Box 68)
  - Wilcox, Leonard I. (Box 68)
  - Wilde, Isabel Carleton (Box 68)
  - Wilde, Oscar (Box 68)
  - Wilder, Thornton (Box 68)
  - Wilgus, Asa, 1934-1940; 1 folder (Box 68)
  - Wilgus, Asa, 1941-1959; undated; 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Wilkinson, Louis Umfreville, A Chaste Man (Box 69)
  - Willeford, Charles Ray (Box 69)
  - William Morris Agency (Box 69)
  - Williams, Albert Rhys (Box 69)
  - Williams, Gil (Box 69)
  - William, Gluyas (Box 69)
  - Williams, Henry Lionel (Box 69)
  - Williams, Joan (Box 69)
  - Williams, Joy (Box 69)
  - Williams, Nathan Boone (Box 69)
  - Williams, Wirt (Box 69)
  - Williams College (Box 69)
  - Williams College Man, Land, 1968 (Box 69)
  - Williams College Man, Land, 1969 (Box 69)
  - Williams College The Williams Advocate (Box 69)
  - Willison, George Findlay (Box 69)
  - Willson, Frank C. (Box 69)
  - Wilner, Herbert (Box 69)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 3 folders (Box 69)
  - Wilson, T.C., See New Letters in America.
  - Wilson, Tal G. (Box 69)
  - Wilson, Walter (Box 69)
  - Wingfield-Stratford, Esme (Box 69)
  - Winslow, Henry F. (Box 69)
  - Winter, Ella, 1934-1949; undated; 2 folders (Box 69)
  - Winther, Sophus Keith (Box 69)
  - Wisconsin Magazine of History (Box 69)
  - Wise, James Waterman (Box 69)
  - Withers, Carl (Box 69)
  - Wodehouse, Pelham Grenville (Box 69)
  - Wolfe, Bertram David (Box 69)
  - Wolfe, Don Marion (Box 69)
  - Wolfert, Ira (Box 69)
  - Wolseley, Roland E. (Box 69)
  - Woltman, Frederick Enos (Box 69)
  - Woman's Home Companion - article on small towns (Box 70)
  - Wood, Charles Erskine Scott (Box 70)
  - Woods, Ralph Louis (Box 70)
  - Woolf, Virginia (Box 70)
  - Work, John McClelland (Box 70)
  - Work Camps for America (Box 70)
  - Workers' Educational Society (Troy, NY) (Box 70)
  - World (Box 70)
  - The World (New York) (Box 70)
  - World Scope Encyclopedia (Box 70)
  - Wortis, Joseph. "Freudianism and the Psychoanalytic Tradition", 1945 (Box 70)
  - Wortis, Joseph. "How Psychology Can Help", 1946 (Box 70)
  - Wouk, Herman (Box 70)
  - Wreszin, Michael (Box 70)
  - Wright, David Rolland (Box 70)
  - Wright, George B. (Box 70)
  - Wright, John (Box 70)
  - Wright, Richard (Box 70)
  - Wright, Thomas H. (Box 70)
  - Wrought, Alexander Voros (Box 70)
  - Wulsin, Lucien (Box 70)
  - Wyllie, Irvin G. (Box 70)
  - Wyoming, University of (Box 70)
  - Y (Box 70)
  - Yaddo
    - Ames, Elizabeth, 1931-1970; undated; 5 folders (Box 71)
    - Hanson, Pauline, 1952-1975; undated; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Executive Director search 1969-1970 (Box 71)
    - Guests, 1970-1971; undated; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1949-1975; undated; 6 folders (Box 71)
    - Yaddo investigation, 1949; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Yaddo Study Committee, 1949-1950; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Yaddo - Reports, 1964-1975; 13 folders (Box 72)
    - Applications/Admissions, 1966-1974; lacks 1968; 5 folders (Box 73)
    - Yaddo library, 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Yaddo memoranda (Box 73)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 73)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 73)
  - Yoken, Melvin B. (Box 74)
  - Young, Arthur Henry (Box 74)
  - Young, Brad (Box 74)
  - Young, Eugene Jared (Box 74)
  - Young, Philip (Box 74)
  - Young, Stanley (Box 74)
  - Young Communist League of the USA (Box 74)
  - Young People's Religious Union, See Writings: The Student Liberal.
  - Youngquist, Albin (Box 74)
  - Yust, Walter, See Encyclopedia Britannica.
  - Z (Box 74)
  - Zacharoff, Lucien (Box 74)
  - Zeigerman, Gerald (Box 74)
  - Ziegler, Abraham (Box 74)
  - Zimmerman, Michael P. (Box 74)
  - Zola, Emile (Box 74)
  - Zuelzer, Wolf W. (Box 74)
  - Zugsmith, Leane (Box 74)
  - Zuver, Dudley (Box 74)
  - Unidentified (Box 74)
- Writings
  - Articles
    See also Literary Horizons column, below.
    - "Aging Sean O'Casey's Latest Memoirs Are Lively, Peevish and Provocative." The New Leader, Nov. 29, 1954 (Box 75)
    - "Aiken: Reality Has Many Levels." The New Leader, Nov. 3, 1952 (Box 75)
    - "Alan Harrington, Gerald Brace Show Good Novels Need Not Be Pessimistic." The New Leader, Sept. 5, 1955 (Box 75)
    - "The American Character Changes." The New Leader, Mar. 12, 1951 (Box 75)
    - "American Culture Isolated." The New Leader, May 20, 1950 (Box 75)
    - "American Fiction Since the War." The English Journal, June 1948 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "The American Novel", Jan. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "American Writers: 1920-1970", Sept. 1973 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Bedford, Sybille. Aldous Huxley: a Biography, Feb. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Behind the Gatsby Phenomenon", May 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Bellow, Saul. Humboldt's Gift, Nov. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Between Friends. (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Books for Christmas", Nov. 1973 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Books to Travel With" (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "'Breakfast of Champions,' and Other Madness", Aug. 1973 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Carr, Virginia Spencer. The Lonely Hunter: a Biography of Carson McCullers, Aug. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "A Dance to the Music of Time,", Dec. 1973 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Different Directions: Rovere, Bellow, Vonnegut" (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Doctorow, E.L. Ragtime, Oct. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Escape to the Wilderness", July 1973 (Box 75)